Jishnu S

Software Engineer | AWS Infra Engineer

Senior software engineer with strong background in software development. More than six years of experience in performing analysis, design, development, testing and application deployment. Developed and implemented client-server applications, web applications and managed cloud infrastructure.



SKILLS



WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Consultant - Application Developer [ThoughtWorks] Viator (Client)

09/2022 - Present Bangalore, India

Viator offers online travel services. It has its online presence as web application and a mobile app. The team is responsible to build new features, analyse and fix bugs and find ways to improve the user experience.

Achievements/Tasks

- Created plugin for Slack and integrated it with the build and release pipeline, to send notifications to users/channel after a successful pipeline production release using **Errbot** library for **Python**.
- Split and configured monolith Gradle project into separate independent projects and upgrade it to Gradle 7.
- Created and deployed custom Gradle plugins using Groovy
- Developer various REST endpoints in Java backend to be consumed by the other microservices.
- Performed code review as per industrial standards.

Senior Consultant - Application Developer [ThoughtWorks] CSIO (Client)

09/2021 - 09/2022 Bangalore, India

ThoughtWorks' engagement with this client involved the migration of inhouse legacy product to AWS cloud with technical and performance improvements. The platform enables the users to send and receive emails.

Achievements/Tasks

- Automated the entire **AWS Cloud** infrastructure deployment using **Terraform** which used the amazon machine images created using **Packer**.
- Designed and configured various AWS services like RDS Postgres, RDS MSSQL, Application load balancers, Route 53,
 Directory Service, SQS, EC2, Autoscaling groups etc and other network layer services like VPC, Subnets, Route tables,
 NAT, NACL, Security Groups etc.
- Created various dashboards in AWS Cloudwatch to visualize valuable application & system metrics.
- Worked extensively in creating **REST APIs** in **Springboot** which is actively consumed by the users to authenticate, and communicate with the mailing server.
- Configured and deployed Apache James mailing server in Amazon EC2 enabling the users to send and receive emails
- Helped to improve the performance of the system by thorough performance analysis at various layers including metrics analysis of each infrastructure components, and coordinating with the QA team to run load tests against the system.
- Created, managed, configured and automated **CI/CD** using **Jenkins**, and imposed strict code analysis and validation rules using **Sonarqube**.
- Played the role of mentor for new folks joining the team.
- · Followed agile methodologies and practices

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer II [Micro Focus] ZENWorks (Product)

10/2019 - 09/2021 Bangalore, India

About the project: Micro Focus ZENworks, a security suite of software products developed and maintained by Micro Focus International.

Achievements/Tasks

- · Built and maintained UI charts components using Angular, which consumed data from backend REST services.
- Developed features and fixed bugs in ZENworks client system software, using C# which supported both Linux and windows devices.
- Developed REST endpoints with Springboot which collected valuable analysis data about malware infected devices from relational database.
- Coordinated with database team to generate queries using **querydsl** framework, which supported multiple relational databases.
- Worked with the team to develop and maintain microservices split from a monolith application.
- Divided and configured monolith projects into multiple sub-projects which used Maven build tool.
- As part of the daily development, worked with docker to build, deploy, configure and debug bot UI and backend applications.
- Configured and managed the team **Jenkins** to collect valuable build and test case execution data to create reports.
- · Involved in various functional enhancements and bug fixes in both frontend and backend applications.
- Followed agile methodologies and practices.

Software Engineer [Tata Consultancy Services] GE Healthcare (Client)

07/2016 - 10/2019 **Bangalore, India About the project:** Enovia is the premiere PLM software solution. This application tracks the entire lifecycle of the product.

Achievements/Tasks

- Developed various data tables and other features using **JSP** which relied on the business layer created using **Java** to fetch necessary data from the database, parse it make it available to the frontend pages.
- · Handled the migration from existing legacy SOAP services to REST and configured the endpoints in Akana API gateway
- Developed feature to import users into 3DPassport which is a centralized authentication system (CAS) which enabled various downstream systems to authenticate with the PLM application and request data.
- Developed scripts using VBScript and in Java for CAS authentication with 3DPassport, which helped the teams who
 managed the downstream systems to add it to their request data process.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Science University Of Calicut

07/2013 - 03/2016 3.2 GPA

LANGUAGES

English Malayalam

Full Professional Proficiency Native or Bilingual Proficiency

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Balasamajam (Flutter Mobile Application)

- This application is responsible for recording and managing money contributions and transactions.
- Tech Stack: Flutter, Springboot, PostgreSQL, EC2, Docker, RDS